MOMIK SHRESTHA

https://momikshrestha.com.np | momik.shrestha@gmail.com | +9779860222338 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/momik

SUMMARY

Software Developer with 3+ years of experience in full-stack development, specializing in Laravel, Vue, Node, and React. Proven track record of delivering complex software solutions for open-source and commercial projects. Experienced in working with EU-based clients and ensuring regulatory compliance. Seeking full-stack roles with a focus on backend development.

SKILLS

- Backend Languages: PHP, Laravel, NodeJS, Typescript, Serverless (Atlas App Services)
- Frontend Languages: CSS, SCSS, Tailwind, Vue3, ¡Query, JS, Typescript, React
- Design patterns: MVC, Repo pattern, Service-repo pattern, Factory pattern, Builder pattern
- Development Tools: Git, Github, GitLab, Postman, Docker, PHPStan, PHPUnit, Bruno
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- API Patterns: REST-ful, SOAP, CKAN
- Documentation: Markdown, Scrabble, SwaggerUI, Excalidraw, Draw.io

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mid-Level Software Engineer | YoungInnovations Pvt. Ltd | March 2024 - Ongoing | Lalitpur, Nepal

- Collaborated across multiple development teams, proactively stepping in as an interim project lead during critical leadership absences
- Served as the primary client communication point, managing communications through professional email and video calls
- Mentored interns and new hires on company processes and tooling, reducing project onboarding time
- Operated as the sole developer and maintainer for critical company projects, ensuring end-to-end development, delivery, and reliability
- Manage project maintenance and feature releases by meticulous breakdown of complex requirements, realistic delivery estimation, and consistently meeting project deadlines while ensuring rigorous compliances are met
- Actively contribute to architectural design and development of sophisticated multi-tenant software
- Technologies: Laravel, Postgres, Docker, TypeScript, Node, Express, MongoDB, Atlas App Services

Junior Backend Engineer | YoungInnovations Pvt. Ltd | Sept. 2022 - March 2024 | Lalitpur, Nepal

- Resolved 30+ technical user-facing bugs reported by users via Zendesk
- Worked on development tickets assigned by senior engineers across multiple projects
- Implemented Unit testing, increasing project-wide coverage from 22% to 74%
- Automated localization process in projects by developing Python and Google Sheets integrations
- Technologies: Laravel, Postgres, Vue, PHPUnit, Postman

Frontend Trainee | Tofu Technovations Pvt. Ltd | March 2020 - April 2021 | Kathmandu, Nepal

- Integrated APIs with frontend components
- Enhanced and maintained legacy projects
- Converted Figma designs into web templates and working prototypes
- Technologies: HTML5, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Git, Github, Figma

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Sciences | Lincoln University College, Malaysia | 2024 - Ongoing

- Relevant Modules: System Design, Data Warehouse & Big Data, Data Analytics, Artificial Intelligence Bachelor's In Computer Application | Tribhuvan University, Nepal | 2018 2023
 - Relevant Modules: Web Technologies, DBMS, Software Development, DSA, Distributed System
 - GPA: 3.40

PROJECTS

IATI Publisher

- Optimized workflows and database queries to improve publish workflow from ~20 minutes to 2 minutes.
- Ensured compliance with EU-GDPR regulations on the IATI Publisher project.
- Integrated third-party services: IATI Registry and IATI Validator.
- Led maintenance and feature releases by working with clients.
- Email communication and weekly sit-downs with foreign clients.

Aidstream

- Maintained and updated the project, including adding tests to enhance code reliability.
- Delivered feature releases and resolved technical bugs to improve platform stability.
- Acted as a full-stack developer working on both the front and the back end.
- Addressed 30+ client-facing issues.

Career Service Center

- Designed, tested, and optimized APIs to ensure seamless functionality.
- Enhanced API performance and scalability for a better user experience.
- Integrated third-party services: Manatal and Moodle.

The Only Ever

- Collaborated with the Obsidian developer community to understand the platform's native APIs.
- Created the Only Ever Obsidian Plugin, integrating seamlessly with the Obsidian ecosystem.
- Sole developer and maintainer for The Only Ever Obsidian Plugin.
- Sole developer and maintainer of The Only Ever Chrome Extension.

Label-Step

- Led the development and release of a major feature during the lead developer's absence
- Collaborated with the client to define feature requirements and ensure smooth deployment.
- Provided post-release support and addressed critical issues to maintain system stability.

NGO-Openbook

- Fixed high-priority bugs and provided ongoing maintenance for platform stability.
- Refactored legacy code to align with modern best practices, improving maintainability.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Lecturer in Web Technologies at ACHS College, teaching undergraduate students (2024).
- Academic Counselor at ACHS College, handling admissions & academic guidance (2023).
- Academic Excellence and Project Defense Award winner (2022).
- Worked as an Admissions Counsellor at ACHS college (2022).
- Regional finalist at Nepal's largest Hackathon (2022).
- OSM workshop, selected participant (2021),